JAMES CLARK

jamesmhclark@gmail.com | +447814040189

PROFILE

A Makers Coding Academy graduate who is currently employed as a Software Engineer at Deloitte. I'm a full stack developer combining strong technical knowledge with training in favoured coding practices, backed by 4 years in broadcast within production/project management roles.

Technical CV: https://github.com/jmsclrk/CV

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-clark-1a6558ba

TECH SKILLS



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full Stack Software Engineer at Deloitte Simulation and Digital Twins

Jun 2021 – Present

- Designed and delivered custom frontend apps using ReactJS.
- Built backend APIs and integrate with complex simulation models.
- Developed, designed, and built complete system architectures.
- Web app lead on client projects, driving development and managing client expectations.
- Managed project plan and DevOps tasks for the web development workstream, allocated work to a team of developers.
- Balanced workload across several client projects, pitches, and internal projects.

Integration Engineer at Avado

Mar 2020 - Feb 2021

- Built and deployed C# web apps that integrated Avado's systems and automated timeconsuming processes.
- Built custom APIs and integrated with numerous 3rd party APIs, developing reusable components to simplify working with external tools and services used by Avado.
- Refactored legacy code to improve performance, structure and reusability.
- Designed well-structured database objects and created complex SQL scripts to transform and cleanse data.
- Scoped tickets to a high standard, code reviewed peers' tickets providing timely feedback.

PROJECTS

GymPad

- React Native / Django REST Framework / Docker.
- Gym tracking notes app.
- Offline management and version control allowing seamless use online, offline and across numerous devices.
- Previously released on iOS/App Store and had been built Android ready. No longer available.
- Developed frontend web interface for interacting with same backend data (TypeScript / React).



Amma Hackney

- React / Django REST Framework.
- Has been taken down, to be redeployed in 2022.
- Website for a new food business offering monthly supper clubs delivered, based in Hackney, London.
- Mobile-first design, a responsive layout snaps between one and two panels depending on screen width.
- Integration with the Google Forms and Gmail APIs.
- Admin area to manage menu, order dates and instructions.
- Worked closely with the stakeholder to build and agree on functionality and an aesthetic that worked for them.



EDUCATION

Makers Academy, Coding Bootcamp University of Bristol, Biological Sciences (2:1) Sep – Dec 2019 2011 – 2014

FURTHER EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Production Manager / Coordinator at Sky Sports, Sky UK

Nov 2017 - Jul 2019

- End-to-end supervision of the complete production process for golf sporting events covered by Sky Sports, worked closely with the Head of Golf to accommodate for up to four golf tournaments per week.
- Managed diverse production teams in Europe and the United States with crew numbers ranging from 20 to 250 people depending on the tier of production.
- Tested the latest technologies, such as virtual reality, and adapted them to Sky's sports coverage to enhance the viewer experience.
- Effectively managed the deadlines and expectations of overlapping production events of different scales and priorities, to ensure all events ran smoothly.
- Co-planned and managed the 2018 Ryder Cup and The Open, Sky Sports' two biggest broadcast events (250+ crew members, £1.5m+ budgets).

Production Coordinator at BBC

May 2016 - Nov 2017

- Developed close relationships with all departments and external contract providers.
- Countered unexpected problems during production with both instant and longer-term solutions to resume filming immediately and prevent recurrence.

Development Researcher at Hungry Bear Media

May 2015 – May 2016

- Ensured the efficient running of the office by centrally supporting all ongoing productions.
- Produced, filmed and edited taster reels for new ideas.